<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Amol Kahat - Meetups/conferences</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/meetupsconferences.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2019-12-01T12:20:00+05:30</updated><subtitle>Blog</subtitle><entry><title>Tor Browser</title><link href="/tor-browser.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-12-01T12:20:00+05:30</published><updated>2019-12-01T12:20:00+05:30</updated><author><name>amolkahat</name></author><id>tag:None,2019-12-01:/tor-browser.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 2019-12-30&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Venue:&lt;/strong&gt; Red Hat India Pvt. Ltd. Pune, MH, India&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meetup Name:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/WoSEC-India-Women-of-Security/events/266136146/"&gt;WoSec and  InfoSecGirls workshop by Kushal Das&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, After long time.. I'm writing blog. Today I went to WoSec amd InfoSecGirls meetup,&lt;br&gt;
and meetup was focused on Tor. Kushal was speaker he talked about&lt;br&gt;
Tor Browser and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 2019-12-30&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Venue:&lt;/strong&gt; Red Hat India Pvt. Ltd. Pune, MH, India&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meetup Name:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/WoSEC-India-Women-of-Security/events/266136146/"&gt;WoSec and  InfoSecGirls workshop by Kushal Das&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, After long time.. I'm writing blog. Today I went to WoSec amd InfoSecGirls meetup,&lt;br&gt;
and meetup was focused on Tor. Kushal was speaker he talked about&lt;br&gt;
Tor Browser and it's services. Here are few things which he covered:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tor is used for anonymity, when you are using Tor no one can track you.&lt;br&gt;
   They can see you are connected to some server but they do not see what you are&lt;br&gt;
   doing there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tor network is part of Dark Network, lot's of .onion sites are hosted using the Tor services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can setup .onion website very easy. You just need to have tor browser installed in your system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let's set it up with Django&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create Simple django project and run it on 80 port.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit &lt;strong&gt;/etc/tor/torrc&lt;/strong&gt; file and uncomment following lines.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HiddenServiceDir /var/lib/tor/hidden_service/&lt;br&gt;
       &amp;gt; HiddenServicePort 80 127.0.0.1:80&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Restart Tor service&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will see there will be one directory in &lt;strong&gt;/var/lib/tor/hidden_services/&lt;/strong&gt;,it will contain one file known as hostname, it will be your .onion link.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tor Browser version: 0.4.x support version 3 addressing. You cold see that your URL will be &lt;strong&gt;siidrba5vbfitbudvyvrm5gg7exiq2sw4y3cy5v4ims26rz24zribeyd.onion&lt;/strong&gt; long. (Note: Version 2 addressing use 16 bit addressing)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put that tor URL link in Tor Browser.. and... here you go.. your website is running in Tor network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setup 16 bit address for our website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit &lt;strong&gt;/etc/tor/torrc&lt;/strong&gt; file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add these lines below the &lt;strong&gt;HiddenServicePort&lt;/strong&gt; line&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HiddenServiceDir /var/lib/tor/service2/  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HiddenServiceVersion 2&lt;br&gt;
HiddenServicePort 80 127.0.0.1:80&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, in above code we are creating one more service to the same website but it will be 16 bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restart Tor service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You could see that now in &lt;strong&gt;/var/lib/tor/service2/&lt;/strong&gt; you could see one more hostname file and it will contain 16 bit &lt;strong&gt;.onion&lt;/strong&gt; url link.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let's see how to setup tor URL link only for specific people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To setup tor service we uncomment few lins in &lt;strong&gt;/etc/tor/torrc&lt;/strong&gt; file. Now let's go and add one more line below our service2.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HiddenServiceDir /var/lib/tor/service2/&lt;br&gt;
       &amp;gt; HiddenServiceVersion 2&lt;br&gt;
       &amp;gt; HiddenServicePort 80 127.0.0.1:80&lt;br&gt;
       &amp;gt; HiddenServiceAuthorizeClient stealth service2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will setup this service for those users whom has the key.&lt;br&gt;
   (Well, key...?, which key...? will see it)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restart Tor service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;cat /var/lib/tor/service2/hostname  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\&amp;lt;.onion url&gt; \&amp;lt;secret&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add that secret to tor Browser's torrc file.&lt;br&gt;
   Location: &lt;strong&gt;\~/Tor_Browser/Browser/TorBrowser/Data/Tor/torrc&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HidServAuth nnaiiplq6zzyrfwj.onion d60/MWahqH2TUEIZLJ+HXB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you are set. Restart Tor Browser. You are able to hit the URL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found Tor very interesting. I love to dig more arount it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Meetups/conferences"></category><category term="tor"></category></entry><entry><title>Science Hack Day India (Oct 14-15)</title><link href="/science-hack-day-india-oct-14-15.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-27T15:22:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-10-27T15:22:00+05:30</updated><author><name>amolkahat</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-10-27:/science-hack-day-india-oct-14-15.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On October 14-15 Science Hack Day (SHD) was organized in &lt;strong&gt;Sankalp Bhumi, Balgvai, Karnataka, India.&lt;/strong&gt; This was the second SHD in India, Before that, it happened on same place a year back, And this was my First SHD event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the beginning, I wondering the what I'm going to do …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On October 14-15 Science Hack Day (SHD) was organized in &lt;strong&gt;Sankalp Bhumi, Balgvai, Karnataka, India.&lt;/strong&gt; This was the second SHD in India, Before that, it happened on same place a year back, And this was my First SHD event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the beginning, I wondering the what I'm going to do in the SHD, what I do I'll explain later. But when I got there I fall in love with the venue. The venue was very awesome, lake view, guest house, and that chair in the balcony from where I was scanning the all the venue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Pune we (Sayan, Akshay, Saptak, Medu, and Amritesh) caught the train for the Belgavi, 13th morning we reach there, and of course, Prof. Pravin Patil and Suyash was there to pick us up. When we reach the venue we met with Farhan who also first time attending the SHD India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That whole day we were busy with meeting the people and doing some other activities, like we done rafting on the lake, cycling on the venue, etc, etc.. In the evening we gather together and started out introduction, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hiteshnd"&gt;Hitesh&lt;/a&gt; is one of the organizers of the SHD India, form itself he started the introduction and then one by one other people started the introduction. He is also security guy who is interested in cyber security/Hacing etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the 14 we wake up and had a breakfast. And gather in the conference hall, that hall was full of the school students, some people who came as a hacker and mentor were there. So after the introduction, we presented our ideas, what we are going to do in the SHD. After the introduction of the mentors we get the best presentation on Aeromodelling, Speaker explained 10 main parts of the plain. You can see me holding the plane in some &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/shd_india"&gt;tweets&lt;/a&gt;. That was a very best session because we were learning from the expert. I have some interest in the flying the planes or designing it so it was very informative to me. After that session speaker shows us how the play fly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We came to the cafeteria and started with the 3D printer and 3D pen. I was there for every event, I was helping for setting up the 3D printer, I was helping to Nisha for 3D pen drawing etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the evening some lighting talks were scheduled, so we all gather in the cafeteria. The first talk was stared by Sayan about the Pycon Pune, then Farhan, he was talking about the creating the games etc., there was one talk about the Silicon wafer, Amol Sir who was presenting the talk and telling us how this Silicon wafer made. Then Gautam Samant talking about the physics behind the bicycle and at last Hitesh was talking about the RAT (Remote Access Trojans).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the evening after the dinner, we gather in the cafeteria for the hacking. We were working on our own laptops. Siddhesh, Sayan, Saptak, Akshay was busy in setting up their 3D printer, and finally, the printer is up and running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the next day, everyone started to complete their hacking idea, I was trying to build one Fedora logo with the LEDs. So it previously designed by someone I started to repair it. And it was up and running. Only two LEDs are not glowing. So that day i got best advice form &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/shakthimaan"&gt;Shakti Kannan&lt;/a&gt; hardware and software and I &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Amolkahat/status/921229485734633472"&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt; it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On that day different events were going on like soldering workshop, Dome building, 3D printer running, etc. I was wondering to see what people were doing and talking to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the finally at the evening Pravin Patil with the students started to fly the Rockets. And at the end of the day which was actually the end of the event we all gather in to the hall, and Hitesh was speking what people have done in that two days, and the hackers were there with their designed ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was really nice event, and I'm waiting to join it again in next year. Till then try to hack the things. :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Meetups/Conferences"></category></entry><entry><title>PyLadie Pune Meetup 7 Jan - 2017</title><link href="/pyladie-pune-meetup-7-jan-2017.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-01-07T20:24:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-01-07T20:24:00+05:30</updated><author><name>amolkahat</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-01-07:/pyladie-pune-meetup-7-jan-2017.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Jan - 2017 &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/PyLadies-Pune/"&gt;PyLadies Meetup&lt;/a&gt; was hosted in the Red Hat India Pvt. Ltd Pune Office. It was hosted by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/anweshasrkr"&gt;Anwesha Sarkar&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/kushaldas"&gt;Kushal Das&lt;/a&gt;. Kushal Das is a CPython core developer, &lt;a href="https://www.python.org/psf/"&gt;PSF&lt;/a&gt; director and member of other communities. Anwesha is a lawyer and she also a member of &lt;a href="https://www.python.org/psf/"&gt;PSF&lt;/a&gt; and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Jan - 2017 &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/PyLadies-Pune/"&gt;PyLadies Meetup&lt;/a&gt; was hosted in the Red Hat India Pvt. Ltd Pune Office. It was hosted by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/anweshasrkr"&gt;Anwesha Sarkar&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/kushaldas"&gt;Kushal Das&lt;/a&gt;. Kushal Das is a CPython core developer, &lt;a href="https://www.python.org/psf/"&gt;PSF&lt;/a&gt; director and member of other communities. Anwesha is a lawyer and she also a member of &lt;a href="https://www.python.org/psf/"&gt;PSF&lt;/a&gt; and other Python community member.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this meetup there was a two talks. First talk given by Kushal Das on System Programming using python. In his talk Kushal introduced os, sys module and explain it how to use it while writing the system related code. Kushal started with the changing directory and environment variables. He also explains the creation, deletion and importance of the environment variables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/paulweveritt"&gt;Paul Everitt&lt;/a&gt; came online. Paul Everitt is &lt;a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/pycharm/"&gt;PyCharm&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/webstorm/"&gt;WebStorm&lt;/a&gt; developer in &lt;a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/"&gt;JetBrains&lt;/a&gt;. He woke up early in the morning to for the PyLadies&lt;!--more--&gt; session. He started his talk. In his talk he introduced the beauty of PyCharm. I never knew that i can do that type of stuff with PyCharm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul talk on the following topics using PyCharm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setup and Running.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Virtual Environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debugging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Git in PyCharm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing Test Cases, Test Case coverage and Profiling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Paul's talk he develop a simple 2D game. It was very simple but awesome. You can see it in the video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks Paul for this session. Not only me but who ever is present in the session they also like it. It was an awesome talk. Thanks &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/kushaldas"&gt;Kushal&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/anweshasrkr"&gt;Anwesha&lt;/a&gt; for hosting this meetup and Red Hat for venue sponsor.&lt;br&gt;
[youtube https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BCCjjV7iPwA]&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Meetups/Conferences"></category><category term="python3"></category><category term="jetbrains"></category><category term="pycharm"></category></entry><entry><title>PyLadies Meetup August-2016</title><link href="/pyladies-meetup-august-2016.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-28T06:24:00+05:30</published><updated>2016-08-28T06:24:00+05:30</updated><author><name>amolkahat</name></author><id>tag:None,2016-08-28:/pyladies-meetup-august-2016.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;August 7, 2016, &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/PyLadies-Pune/events/233063341/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PyLadies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; meetup was organized in &lt;strong&gt;Red Hat India Pvt. Ltd&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;PyLadies&lt;/strong&gt; community is working for Open Source contribution of women. &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/PyLadies-Pune/events/233063341/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PyLadies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; community is working to encourage the women to working in Open Source community. In India very few women contribute in Open Source community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/PyLadies-Pune/events/233063341/"&gt;PyLadies&lt;/a&gt; event …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;August 7, 2016, &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/PyLadies-Pune/events/233063341/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PyLadies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; meetup was organized in &lt;strong&gt;Red Hat India Pvt. Ltd&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;PyLadies&lt;/strong&gt; community is working for Open Source contribution of women. &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/PyLadies-Pune/events/233063341/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PyLadies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; community is working to encourage the women to working in Open Source community. In India very few women contribute in Open Source community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/PyLadies-Pune/events/233063341/"&gt;PyLadies&lt;/a&gt; event starts with the talk of &lt;strong&gt;Nisha Menon,&lt;/strong&gt; she talk about the &lt;strong&gt;Basic Communication skill&lt;/strong&gt; in the Open Source community. As she explained about the etiquette of mailing list, communication tools (IRC, Messaging software, etc.).  This was an awesome talk. She highlighted one point which i notice that "&lt;strong&gt;Community is more important than the code !!&lt;/strong&gt;."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes. I started with &lt;strong&gt;PythonPune&lt;/strong&gt; community and today I'm in Red Hat because of the &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/PythonPune/"&gt;PythonPune&lt;/a&gt; Community. Today i supporting and organizing the &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/PythonPune/"&gt;PythonPune&lt;/a&gt; events. This is small contribution from my side to the Community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the Nisha's talk &lt;strong&gt;Kushal&lt;/strong&gt; started video session of &lt;strong&gt;[Jacob Kaplan-Moss]{.full},&lt;/strong&gt; who gave talk in the &lt;strong&gt;Pychon-15&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that we have 45 min of lunch break. Then Chandan started his presentation. His session was completely hands-on session. In his session he covered the following topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strings in the Python with its inbuilt functions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strings with the for loop, List comprehension.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OS module&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;File operations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chandan explain it from very basics. This is one of the good session of basics. Thanks Chandan, Thanks Kushal, Anwesha, Nisha, for conducting this session. This is very good activity which they are doing for ladies to contribute in FOSS.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Meetups/Conferences"></category><category term="python3"></category></entry><entry><title>April Fedora Meetup - 2016</title><link href="/april-fedora-meetup-2016.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-24T19:39:00+05:30</published><updated>2016-04-24T19:39:00+05:30</updated><author><name>amolkahat</name></author><id>tag:None,2016-04-24:/april-fedora-meetup-2016.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;April Fedora meetup was held in Kushal Das's home in jasmenium, magarpatta city Pune at 6 PM evening. This time fedora meetup take new turn which was very exciting. Officially this meetup was about discussing RPM packaging and migration of python2 to python3. But Kushal and Pravenn Kumar change the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;April Fedora meetup was held in Kushal Das's home in jasmenium, magarpatta city Pune at 6 PM evening. This time fedora meetup take new turn which was very exciting. Officially this meetup was about discussing RPM packaging and migration of python2 to python3. But Kushal and Pravenn Kumar change the meetup agenda at the spot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They gave small test cases to everyone (attendees). And tell them to write test cases for that, using python unittest framework. The test cases was some Linux commands which we can break like adduser, deluser, mount, umount etc. That was cool many peoples was completed their task easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazing thing that the test cases which we wrote, those test cases going to merge in fedora testing repository. That was my first Open Source contribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Kushal's home i met his daughter, her name is "&lt;strong&gt;Py&lt;/strong&gt;", she is may be 2 yrs old. I was curious about her name,  i think that Kushal kept her name after "&lt;strong&gt;Pie&lt;/strong&gt;", one another Red Hat Employee. Who was active member in Red Hat's mailing list. So i ask Kushal that you kept her name after Pie?. So he's reply was "No, we kept her name after Python". "Py" her name is as cute as python and she is as cute as python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks Kushal, Pravin and Chandan to host meetup. Thank you &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/anweshasrkr"&gt;Anwesha&lt;/a&gt; for snakes and cold drinks.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Meetups/Conferences"></category><category term="fedora"></category><category term="python3"></category></entry><entry><title>Magical Vim - 02 : The Pulgins</title><link href="/magical-vim-02-the-pulgins.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-24T18:52:00+05:30</published><updated>2016-04-24T18:52:00+05:30</updated><author><name>amolkahat</name></author><id>tag:None,2016-04-24:/magical-vim-02-the-pulgins.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today i arranged the Vim meetup. It was conducted by Dev and his friend. This meetup was organised in &lt;a href="http://piic.co.in/"&gt;PIIC, warje Pune&lt;/a&gt;. One of the friend of mine Shishir Vaidya from PIIC, helps me to organize the meetup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vim meetup was cool. &lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/Pune-vim-users/members/183066483/"&gt;Ganesh&lt;/a&gt; friend of Dev he explained vim plugins …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today i arranged the Vim meetup. It was conducted by Dev and his friend. This meetup was organised in &lt;a href="http://piic.co.in/"&gt;PIIC, warje Pune&lt;/a&gt;. One of the friend of mine Shishir Vaidya from PIIC, helps me to organize the meetup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vim meetup was cool. &lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/Pune-vim-users/members/183066483/"&gt;Ganesh&lt;/a&gt; friend of Dev he explained vim plugins. He explained many plugins. I did't know about this plugins and i never think about that. First he explains about &lt;a href="https://github.com/vim-airline/vim-airline"&gt;Vim-Airline&lt;/a&gt; plugin which is used to decorate the vim. It is an awesome plugin with cool themes. I liked it and sure i'm going to install it in my laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if you get Git integration in vim to code analysis? Yeah that plugin is vim &lt;a href="https://github.com/airblade/vim-gitgutter"&gt;gitgutter&lt;/a&gt;. So if you modified any git repository file it will show you modified lines. With this plugin you can use git commands like add, commit, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that was the main topic in vim meetup. Ajay also explains different plugins in short, like &lt;a href="https://github.com/tpope/vim-fugitive"&gt;fugitive&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://github.com/xolox/vim-notes"&gt;note&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://github.com/Valloric/YouCompleteMe"&gt;YouComplteteMe&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://github.com/scrooloose/nerdtree"&gt;Nerdtree&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://github.com/VundleVim/Vundle.vim"&gt;vundle&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://github.com/Lokaltog/vim-powerline"&gt;powerline&lt;/a&gt; etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually this meetup was short but great and I like it. Thanks Ganesh and Dev to organize this meetup. Thanks PIIC for arrangements.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Meetups/Conferences"></category><category term="Vim"></category></entry></feed>